<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href=""?>
<Journal>
    <Year number="2025">
        <Month name="June" number="6">
            <Day name="Monday" number="9">
                <Log>
                    I have encountered many ads recently, most notably on Youtube shorts, aiming to deal with people's sense of dissatisfaction in their lives.
                    My opinion of these ads has always been that they are ridiculous services for ridiculous people who are a product of these shitty times.
                    Social media companies constantly try to push their profit margins by making people using their services feel special, heard, and deeply connected to the communities around them.
                    But how far can you push this without becoming delusional? Not very far in my opinion. So many believe in this delusion pushed by social media and may not even realise it.
                    Look, these services like Liven may be good for some but I look at these ads and think if you are someone who needs this, why not try questioning your understanding of suffering?
                    What is your relationship to suffering? Do you feel like you deserve to feel unpleasant emotions? Expose this modern myth of perfection that the social media companies try so hard to push.
                    To be free is hardly a physical state, it's mostly a mental exercise. No one can be free if they are, say, afraid of embarrassing themselves.
                    Yet even myself in my moments of weakness find myself running from embarrassment, acting completely out of fear. But at least I'm working on conquering that fear.
                    Woe to those that do not find themselves even on this path.
                    "Life is shit. I don't deserve this." The irony, there in that statement, lies the source of the suffering.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Tuesday" number="10">
                <Log>
                    Thought about stopping by Myer to buy myself a heavy blanket after work today but opted instead to attend the weekly run club.
                    Surprising energy level during the run given I had felt quite tired in the afternoon, and the weather was cold. First time running Tuesday night with a hoodie.
                    Someone asked me at the dinner afterwards about work and whether the job pays well. 
                    I jokingly replied that you could earn more as an electrician than an electrical engineer, but yes it does pay well.
                    That probably was a stupid thing to say and reveals if anything that my career is in its infancy. But anyways it's one of those things you say when you're tired and the conversation is moving too fast.
                    Truly what I wished to answer with was "it pays enough". That is my genuine answer to paycheck related questions.
                    Because once it is enough for me to live comfortably, money is no longer a concern really. My primary concern is the freedom and creativity in the work.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Thursday" number="12">
                <Log>
                    Bought that quilt (discovered they're not marketed as "blankets") today. Paid for a cheap one at first. On my way out saw a premium quilt that was 60% off so decided to go back and swap it.
                    It's 85% down, 15% feather apparently.
                    I don't understand why I feel no urge to document my life in photographs. It's fascinating to see other's lives illustrated in such a way, why don't I do it myself?
                    I will try and make a real concerted effort to do so very soon... Maybe I'll aim for the winter solstice, yes that can be my deadline.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Sunday" number="15">
                <Log>
                    I, I had a dream once. That I would make music, and that it would be heard by many. At the time, I did not quite know why this was a dream of mine. But now, that I understand the vitality of communication, it is clear to me.
                    I wanted to be heard, to be understood, to be liberated through an expression of one's fundamental self.
                    A shame that I was still imprisoned by those forces of anxiety, I only had a feeling and did not understand the actual nature of communication.
                    It's fundamentality, it's centrality to being. How being on a stage and performing is not just something one does, it is oneself. 
                    You exist in that moment and that is actually all there is. 
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Saturday" number="21">
                <Log>
                    Well, today is June 21 2025, the winter solstice. Reading my log from June 12 I am reminded of my goal to have contributed something
                    of myself to the greatest human network of all time that is the internet. 
                    I have nothing prepared. This week has been busy at work. And I was afflicted with a mild headache from Wednesday onwards which is only just
                    easing up now, thank God. I wonder if that lingering discomfort was caused by sniffing that toxic weed at community volunteering on Tuesday.
                    Green Cestrum... That's what it was. Dude leading the volunteer bush regeneration party was perhaps a bit too nonchalant about its toxicity.
                    Anyways, just glad to be feeling like myself again.
                </Log>
                <Reflection>
                    Most of my youth was spent in a state of suppression. Of constant anxiety about one thing or another, whether it be social relationships
                    or something entirely inanimate such as radiation. There would be periods where I would be paralyzed by this particular fear of radiation, I even wrote an email
                    to some scientific agency once asking if staples I perceived as being warm contained radioisotopes.
                    The previous example of a concern of mine is entirely ridiculous, and I have the ability now to just see it that way and consign such idiocy to the void.
                    Same goes for basically all of the anxieties that I had. So I was trapped in what was a self-constructed, purely mental cage of anxiety.
                    Afraid to speak out in social settings, worrying obsessively over benign details like garbage bins. 
                    Even though the cage was not real, it was still so utterly repressive nonetheless, and my freedom, creativity, and ability to express myself suffered so greatly
                    during this period of adolescence and young adulthood. 
                    At the time I could not draw these lines. I couldn't see that the deep unhappiness and sense of being trapped was a mental construction.
                    The tumultuous times that followed, the need for an escape, the hedonism, the seeking to be numb of all the fear. None of that needs much of an explanation 
                    considering that I was a prisoner of my own mind (am I still today? Certainly some traces are still there).
                    At its most intense, my fear of death was driving me to wish for death. There's an interesting converse here. Since I stopped fearing death so much I stopped wishing for it too.
                </Reflection>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Sunday" number="22">
                <Log>
                    I have just started on a new audiobook, Precision by Simon Winchester. After the first chapter it strikes me that in all my years of study of engineering there was little mention
                    of the history, of stories of the great heroes in this field that you might find in other, more "soft" fields such as literature.
                    Working engineers, just from observation, can often become quite jaded, frustrated, and overall uninspired by their work. Where's the awareness of great figures in engineering such as
                    John Wilkinson that I have just been learning about, and the desire to emulate their achievements. 
                    This is more a trait, I find, of the humanities, where people working in this field have heroes and a more emotional connection to the work.
                    I venture that Engineers too should have this sort of relationship to the work. We should have heroes that we admire, and a fundamentally emotional connection to the things that are worked on.
                    Real engineering is no less exquisitely creative and emotional than the creation of an artistic masterpiece. And just as the masterpiece does for the artist, 
                    great works of engineering should provide a window into the soul of the engineer.
                </Log>
            </Day>
        </Month>
        <Month name="August" number="8">
            <Day name="Sunday" number="17">
                <Log>
                    I tried out something quite interesting today after binocular vision was mentioned in this book I was reading.
                    I thought that it should be possible to see both sides of a flat plane if it was placed in the right position.
                    And so I brought a card up between my eyes, perpendicular to my face, and what I saw was interesting.
                    Yes I could see both sides of the card, but not simultaneously. I could consciously shift focus from one eye to the other and thus see the other side.
                    But both at once? That vision simply did not appear to me. And another thing, if I looked straight ahead I hardly noticed the card at all.
                </Log>
            </Day>
        </Month>
        <Month name="September" number="9">
            <Day name="Tuesday" number="16">
                <Log title="Logs lead to shutting out of portion of dating pool">
                    Sometimes I'll view social media content from some of my left leaning/politically active gay friends on social media and it'll give me a sense of dread.
                    Because regardless of whatever the current affairs are, every now and again they will make content cancelling someone they once admired for differing on just a single point.
                    And, again regardless of whatever the topic might be, this fills me with dread for just, being able to form lasting relationships with others. I wonder how can a relationship be maintained with anyone like this, 
                    because even if I am 100% aligned with someone's views, to err is human. 
                    Let's say I am so aligned with someone's views that 99% of the times we interact we are in agreement. 
                    It only takes 69 interactions before the chance of at least one unfavourable interaction slipping in exceeds 50%. Now were I to pursue a relationship with them where, let's say I interact with them twice a day on average,
                    there is effectively a 50% chance of the relationship failing within a month (presuming that a difference in opinion is something totally irredeemable, as some of my friend's social media posts time and time again show). 
                    After a year's time, there is just a mere 0.065% chance of the relationship still lasting intact (assuming 2 interactions per day throughout that year).
                    Now let's say I really go mad and want a 5 year relationship that has at least a 75% chance of making it through those 5 years. Again let us assume that we talk about two contentious topics per day.
                    Were I to be so hapless that my partner is one of these political activist types. I would need an astonishing agreement rate of 99.992% for each and every interaction.
                    Basically, I would be a slave to their opinion. Now, that doesn't sound so progressive does it. Almost, dare I say, authoritarian.
                    Though I suppose there is another option. Talking about contentious news twice a day hardly seems necessary. Let's say it unfortunately creeps in once a week. Then I only need to agree with them 99.89% of the time for a 75% chance that the relationship survives 5 years.
                    Were it just once a month, 99.52% agreement required.
                    But, I contend that this is no way to live either. I have always been drawn to news and current affairs. That sense of FOMO feels like its built into the fibres of my existence. Being forced to share my thoughts just once a month, to me would be just another form of slavery.
                    And so, I bid any realistic prospect of a healthy and happy life with a political activist, adieu.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Tuesday" number="23">
                <Log>
                    Doesn't take much for us to slip the surly bonds of Earth. All politics aside, ever since the Kirk assassination, life's fragile and fleeting nature has been more present in my mind. 
                    That might sound silly to some given that every day people die in ways more cruel and horrific than Charlie Kirk. But I saw the video. Seeing someone die is different and it is odd that that video was so easily accessible.
                    Would have thought society would be censored from seeing a brutal death like that.
                    And so life's fragile and fleeting nature is at the fore, compounded by other things too. Like when I broke my leg in a cycling accident, and when my mother fell ill and eventually passed away. 
                    Sometime ago in this log book I think I wrote something like I'm not afraid of Death. Maybe my mental state was poor back then. Truthfully I most definitely care. 
                    Can't look into that void without feeling like gripping on tight to this life and this moment that I have. That's a fear of Death for sure.
                </Log>
            </Day>
        </Month>
        <Month name="November" number="11">
            <Day name="Friday" number="28">
                <Log>
                    I've started to think that I am growing weary of the city. Just shy of 2 years, and 5 months I have lived here now, just outside the northwest corner of Surry Hills.
                    I had been filled with excitement to come here. Not just for the convenience of attending to my duties at the University of Sydney (at the time), but also for being around people and around the center of the action.
                    I wanted to know what love was, and it seemed like the bustling heart of the city was the right place to find out.
                    Or perhaps I was just addicted to the chaos and excitement. A yearning for adventure.
                    Those wants are passing me by.
                    Eventually, a simple life with people that I love will be all that I wish for.
                </Log>
            </Day>
        </Month>
    </Year>
</Journal>