<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href=""?>
<Journal>
    <Year number="2025">
        <Month name="June" number="6">
            <Day name="Monday" number="9">
                <Log>
                    I have encountered many ads recently, most notably on Youtube shorts, aiming to deal with people's sense of dissatisfaction in their lives.
                    My opinion of these ads has always been that they are ridiculous services for ridiculous people who are a product of these shitty times.
                    Social media companies constantly try to push their profit margins by making people using their services feel special, heard, and deeply connected to the communities around them.
                    But how far can you push this without becoming delusional? Not very far in my opinion. So many believe in this delusion pushed by social media and may not even realise it.
                    Look, these services like Liven may be good for some but I look at these ads and think if you are someone who needs this, why not try questioning your understanding of suffering?
                    What is your relationship to suffering? Do you feel like you deserve to feel unpleasant emotions? Expose this modern myth of perfection that the social media companies try so hard to push.
                    To be free is hardly a physical state, it's mostly a mental exercise. No one can be free if they are, say, afraid of embarrassing themselves.
                    Yet even myself in my moments of weakness find myself running from embarrassment, acting completely out of fear. But at least I'm working on conquering that fear.
                    Woe to those that do not find themselves even on this path.
                    "Life is shit. I don't deserve this." The irony, there in that statement, lies the source of the suffering.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Tuesday" number="10">
                <Log>
                    Thought about stopping by Myer to buy myself a heavy blanket after work today but opted instead to attend the weekly run club.
                    Surprising energy level during the run given I had felt quite tired in the afternoon, and the weather was cold. First time running Tuesday night with a hoodie.
                    Someone asked me at the dinner afterwards about work and whether the job pays well. 
                    I jokingly replied that you could earn more as an electrician than an electrical engineer, but yes it does pay well.
                    That probably was a stupid thing to say and reveals if anything that my career is in its infancy. But anyways it's one of those things you say when you're tired and the conversation is moving too fast.
                    Truly what I wished to answer with was "it pays enough". That is my genuine answer to paycheck related questions.
                    Because once it is enough for me to live comfortably, money is no longer a concern really. My primary concern is the freedom and creativity in the work.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Thursday" number="12">
                <Log>
                    Bought that quilt (discovered they're not marketed as "blankets") today. Paid for a cheap one at first. On my way out saw a premium quilt that was 60% off so decided to go back and swap it.
                    It's 85% down, 15% feather apparently.
                    I don't understand why I feel no urge to document my life in photographs. It's fascinating to see other's lives illustrated in such a way, why don't I do it myself?
                    I will try and make a real concerted effort to do so very soon... Maybe I'll aim for the winter solstice, yes that can be my deadline.
                </Log>
            </Day>
            <Day name="Sunday" number="15">
                <Log>
                    I, I had a dream once. That I would make music, and that it would be heard by many. At the time, I did not quite know why this was a dream of mine. But now, that I understand the vitality of communication, it is clear to me.
                    I wanted to be heard, to be understood, to be liberated through an expression of one's fundamental self.
                    A shame that I was still imprisoned by those forces of anxiety, I only had a feeling and did not understand the actual nature of communication.
                    It's fundamentality, it's centrality to being. How being on a stage and performing is not just something one does, it is oneself. 
                    You exist in that moment and that is actually all there is. 
                </Log>
            </Day>
        </Month>
    </Year>
</Journal>